<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby RSS feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[An extension of the gatsby starter blog, with support for MDX]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 06:09:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Atomic Habits]]></title><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-mdx-demo.netlify.com/atomic-habits/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-mdx-demo.netlify.com/atomic-habits/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 13:52:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’ve followed James Clear’s blog during my college days, and I found his productivity tips immensely useful. I was delighted to hear that he wrote a book about habits. Honestly, I didn’t rush into the book despite how good his &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesclear.com/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; was. Having read Charles Duhigg’s Power of Habit, I felt like I didn’t need to pursue this book since I already know the whole concept of how habits are formed. I gave it a read anyway, and I wished I read this sooner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Why I love this book&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This book is full of action-packed insights on pushing through the habits you set. I love the many examples he tackled in the book whether exercising, meditating, or losing weight. I got a lot out of each chapter, and I love the emphasis of starting small each day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How it changed my life&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I read a chapter, where you should first standardize instead of optimizing. Sometimes, we get too hungover with how the perfect routine should look like when what really matters more is showing up. I stopped overthinking the optimal ways of performing the habit and just started doing it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I downloaded the Calm app and got back into meditating and gratitude journal-ling. I focused mainly on how I could consistently perform these habits. I used to do 10 minutes of meditation but decided to make it 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Who should read this?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend you read this if you’re looking to break out of your bad habits. The book will definitely help you understand why you continuously perform bad habits even if you’re well aware of the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book is also a great read to help you find small ways to incorporate positive habits into your life. You’ll definitely find something that’ll work into your daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Creating a Japan COVID-19 Tracker using Mapbox GL JS and d3.js]]></title><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-mdx-demo.netlify.com/mapbox-exam/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-mdx-demo.netlify.com/mapbox-exam/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 13:52:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was taking up the Mapbox GL JS exam, and I decided that I wanted to fully flex my web development skills for this exam. I used a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ryo-ma/covid19-japan-web-api#data-sources&quot;&gt;COVID-19 Japan API&lt;/a&gt; that was updated daily. It was pretty straightforward to use with the necessary data points I wanted to project onto a map. I visualized all prefectures of Japan with their corresponding cases and tests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/cd130894130b4e3f51f38296a6494eb7/covid-japan.gif&quot; alt=&quot;COVID-19 Japan Prefectures&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using d3.js, I visualized the trend of daily cases and tests added. The case breakdown wasalso visualized by &lt;span class=&quot;StyledText-sc-1sadyjn-0 hLQYPQ&quot;&gt;Severe&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;StyledText-sc-1sadyjn-0 ycxWT&quot;&gt;Active&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;StyledText-sc-1sadyjn-0 bOEhWM&quot;&gt;Recovered&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class=&quot;StyledText-sc-1sadyjn-0 bJgQjq&quot;&gt;Death&lt;/span&gt; through a stacked bar chart. I love the animations when hovering over from one prefecture to another.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a fun web application to build in my past time, and well worth the time spent developing. For the record, I passed the Mapbox exam. I’m looking forward to building more web applications using Mapbox.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the link to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://covid-japan.web.app/&quot;&gt;tracker&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>